英格兰，公元1215年，
England, in the year 1215,
约翰王在位已经十六年
had been under the reign of King John for 16 years.
作为英格兰有史以来最恶毒的统治者，
The most villainous of England's monarchs,
战败给法国而闻名的约翰王，
John was renowned for losing wars with France,
横征暴敛，
levying punitive taxes,
奸淫无度
and sleeping with the wives of barons.
贵族们被迫反抗他们的约翰王了
The barons finally rebelled against their king,
注定要爆发一场血腥的内战
and became locked in a bloody civil war
内战持续了三年多，双方的战力都遭到了重创
lasting for over three years and decimating both armies.
期间，圣殿骑士团也被卷入了这场冲突之中
In time, the Knights Templar were drawn into this conflict.
在这些训练有素的圣殿骑士的帮助下，
With the help of these highly trained warrior monks,
约翰王和他的军队被彻底地打败了
King John and his royal army were eventually defeated.
约翰王想保住他的王位，
It was agreed that John could remain on the throne,
一个先决条件...
on one condition...
那就是签署一个宪章
that he would sign a document
赋予平民享受自由的权利
upholding the rights and privileges of all free men,
同时抑制王权
but ultimately limiting the power of the monarchy.
签字生效！
Make it count.
约翰在温莎堡附近的伦尼米德签署《大宪章》
The Magna Carta was sealed at Runnymede
时间是公元1215年6月15日
on the 15th of June in the year of our Lord 1215.
《大宪章》事件将被载入史册
It will be remembered throughout history.
但世人忘却的是宪章签署后发生的事
(本片故事改编自英国历史上伟大的罗切斯特城堡保卫战)
What is not remembered is what King John did next.
陛下?
Sire?
到时间了。
It's time.
(英格兰南部海岸)
Hyah!
(丹麦雇佣军集结中)
Hyah! Hyah!
英格兰欢迎你
England welcomes you.
教皇信守承诺？
Does the Pope hold his word?
噢，要有信心啊，泰伯瑞斯队长
Oh, how have faith, Captain Tiberius.
他在等你按约定行动的消息呢
His Eminence is waiting to hear you hold to yours.
他承诺过教会会保障你的权益
The Church will stay out of your lands, you have his word.
那我们将帮你重新掌控这个国家
We'll get your country back.
来者何人？
What say you?
我叫埃伯特-马修斯. 我们来躲避暴风雪
Abbot Marcus. We seek shelter from the storm.
开打城门！
Open the gates!
快来帮忙
Come and help.
你跑这里来有事吗？
What business do you have here?
我的任务是去坎特伯雷处理教会事务。我们只是来躲雨
Our business is with God at Canterbury. We need only shelter.
当然可以来躲雨，还有美食
Shelter you shall have. Food also.
你对待天主的仆人太周到了
You treat the Lord's servants well.
你带着的圣殿骑士团徽章，可你没有佩剑
You wear the mark of the Templars, yet you carry no swords.
这些人不再需要打仗了
These men have no more need to fight.
圣殿骑士团不佩剑就心怀信念到处走？
Templars masking their faith and travelling without swords.
好高尚啊！
How noble!
老天爷作证，男爵，这些人光明正大
As God is our witness, Baron, these men have nothing to hide.
埃伯特，别自欺欺人了，骑士团曾经与国王为敌
Abbot, save your benedictions. The Templars fought against the King.
现在你睡在国王的城堡里。这些人需要隐藏的东西可多着呢
Now you sleep in a king's castle. These men have plenty to hide.
那个你。你说呢？
You there. What say you?
他们没啥可说的。他们保持沉默誓言
They say nothing. They hold vows of silence.
沉默的骑士团。很好
Templars without tongues. Very well.
明早就离开
Just be gone by the morning.
往里退！
Back inside!
马歇尔
Marshal.
当我接受监护那些宣誓沉默的人
When I accept guardianship over men who take the vows of silence,
首先他们会告诉我是什么让他们来找我
I'm also informed of what led them to me in the first place.
我了解圣殿骑士团把沉重的负担交给了你
I know the Templars placed a heavy burden on you.
我知道你疤痕累累
I know you're deeply scarred.
你罩衫上的十字架
The cross on your tunic
是神的意愿下你的信念的象征
is a symbol of your faith in God's will.
你现在感到迷茫
It should not be full of the torment it now bears upon your soul.
我们到达坎特伯雷之时，
When we arrive at Canterbury,
我会讨论你从圣殿骑士团退役的事情
I'm requesting your leave from the Order of the Knights Templar.
守备！
Garrison men!
约翰王
King John!
大家，去大门那！国王来了！
Men, to the gates! It's the King!
给国王开门！
Open the gates for the King!
Psst!
马歇尔, 你见过皇家的彩旗？
Marshal, did you see royal colours?
达尔奈，那是你的亲手签的吧？
Is that your hand, Darnay?
被逼的，殿下
Forced, Your Highness.
贵族们要挟我，逼迫我签字背叛你
The barons threatened my life, forcing me to sign it and betray you.
我了解这个感受
I know the feeling.
吊死他！
Hang him!
必须制止这种疯狂行为
This insanity must cease.
开门。我们不能坐视不管
Open the door. His quarrel is not with us.
如果国王看到你们仨，必死无疑！
If you three stand before the King, there will be nothing but death.
达尔奈，你太多幸运啊。看来你还不能马上死
What good fortune, Darnay. It seems you will have your last rites.
我主，圣殿骑士团
My Lord, Templars.
他和圣殿骑士团一起前往坎特伯雷
He's travelling en route to Canterbury with Templars.
我怎么有幸让教会的人光临我的城堡了？
To what do I owe the pleasure of the Church visiting my castle?
陛下，我们来躲雨。达尔奈男爵热情地接待了我们
We were in the storm, sire. Baron Darnay granted us your hospitality.
- 我们？      - 我随行的牧师
- We?         - My fellow priests.
啊，对，我听到了
Ah, yes, I heard.
圣殿骑士团
Templars.
陛下，我们作为非武装人员来你的城堡。不是来找茬
Sire, we entered your castle as unarmed men. We seek no fight.
埃伯特,你还记不记得
Are you aware, Abbot,
你在伦尼米德逼迫我签字的事？
that your kind stood at Runnymede and forced my signature,
现在你却还在大言不惭
and now you sleep under my roof?
殿下，我们只是赶往坎特伯雷
Your Highness, we travel to Canterbury
毫无恶意
with simple articles of faith.
我请求你大发慈悲让我们通过
I ask your mercy that we may pass.
那我会大发慈悲的
And I will grant you the same mercy
和当初教会与贵族“大发慈悲”对待我一样
that the Church and the barons of this country bestowed unto me.
"以其人之道, 还治其人之身"，不对吗？Abbot
"Do unto others", isn't that right, Abbot?
泰伯瑞斯
Tiberius!
别让他溜走了
Don't let him go!
快跑！
Ride!
牺牲
There is worth...
总存在它的价值
..in every death.
现在我会继承你的遗愿
And I will see it now in yours.
- 你见到国王了？       - 对，他也见过我了。
- You saw the King?    - Yes. And he saw me.
Mm.
没想到他竟然这么残暴
I didn't imagine that even he was capable of such cruelty.
埃伯特-马修斯是好样的
Abbot Marcus was the finest of men.
告诉我，他为什么要考虑你退役的事？
Tell me, why did he request that you leave the Order?
- 我并没想退役                                 - 你答非所问
- Your Grace, I did not wish to be dismissed.  - But that's not what I asked.
我们曾在圣光照耀的土地上？
You were in the Holy Lands?
哈，某些人回来保卫我们的信念
Hm. Some men have returned from defending our faith
只是为了解开他们心中的疑惑
only to find themselves questioning it.
现在你扪心自问，托马斯
Now you must ask yourself, Thomas.
在你心中的...
what is in your heart?
是起义抑或复仇？
Rebellion or revenge.
我觉得这个和国王的所做所为没什么不同
I suppose it makes no difference as the King has the devil in his.
我不管他有没有和教皇说了什么！现在我得去见他
I don't care if he's talking to the Pope! I have to see him now!
当我们说到那个浑蛋...
And as we speak of the devil...
尊敬的大主教
My Lord Archbishop.
我听说了达尔奈男爵的事情
They told me about Darnay.
我们曾经和约翰王达成妥协
We took John at his word...
但现在他又扩建了军队
and now he raises a bitch's army with God's teeth.
我不会向看到血就尿裤子的国王屈服
I'll bow to no king with piss for blood!
这位是托马斯-马歇尔,    这位是威廉de奥尔巴尼男爵
Baron William de Albany, Brother Thomas Marshal.
托马斯直接从达尔奈领地过来的
Brother Thomas comes directly from Darnay Castle.
你要原谅男爵，他说话从来都糙了点
You must forgive our Baron, his tongue is not always so profane.
现在，你该知道罗马教廷支持国王
Now, you should know that Rome sides with the King.
教皇赞成国王对埃伯特-马修斯所做的事？
And the Pope would bless what the King did to Abbot Marcus?
或多或少吧
More or less.
《大宪章》的事我会和教廷沟通下
I am to be excommunicated for writing Magna Carta.
- 多久时间我们才能知道教皇的意见？   - 天知道
- How long have we got?              - God knows.
这...
Your Grace, this...
..国王...必须被制止
..king...must be stopped.
我无法要求你作战，托马斯
I cannot, in all honesty, ask you to fight, Thomas,
但如果你选择拿起剑，将得到我的祝福
but if you choose to take up your sword, you have my blessing.
好兆头
It's a good omen.
上帝与我们同在
God is with us.
法国路易王子的军队有可能会加入我们
Prince Louis has an army may be persuaded to join us.
找法国人帮忙...
Asking the French for help...
对付邪恶的人
that's cursing the blind for the wicked.
如果约翰王走了通往伦敦的多佛大道
If John takes the Dover Road to London
他不得不从中路越过罗彻斯特城堡
he has to cross the Medway here at Rochester.
我会夺取罗彻斯特城堡
I'll seize Rochester Castle.
拖住他们。为你和法国人的谈判赢得点时间
Delay them. That'll give you time to negotiate with the French.
我们没有军队对抗国王
We have no force to fight the King.
我能想办法召集一些人
I have a few men I can count on.
绝不行！以卵击石这样的自杀式的办法不行，男爵
Absolutely not. Suicide is a sin in the eyes of the Church, Baron.
我眼前只有一件事
Your Grace, I'm afraid I only see one thing.
从罗彻斯特，国王能调遣军队和物资
From Rochester, the King is able to dispatch his troops and supplies
全国各地汇聚的
all over the country.
这个是他的基石。不夺取该城堡我们无法阻止他
It is his keystone. Without it we will not stop him.
我不入地狱谁入地狱
All my sins to this.
但愿上帝庇佑我们的计划
May God protect what we are about to do.
小伙子
Guy!
护卫!
Squire!
你们都回去
I want you to ride back.
不，我要去打仗
No. I know how to fight.
你看到他如何和我说话的?
You see how he talks to me?
有杀过人吗？护卫。嗯？
Have you ever killed a man, Squire? Eh?
- 这并不是闹着玩的                              - 为了自由而战不值得吗？
- Then you will learn, it is not a noble thing. - Not even when it's for freedom?
即便为上帝而杀人也不是君子之行
Not even when it is for God.
驾！
Hah!
看你！
Look at you!
我不会放过你们任何一个人
Any one of you throws a turd or a bean, I'll get you!
即使变成鬼
And you know I will! Yargh!
- 刽子手呢？                    - 那边
- Where's the butchers?         - Over there.
我会记住你们
I'll remember your faces!
羊毛剪！锋利！锋利的羊毛剪
Sheep shears! They're sharp! Sharp sheep shears!
- 找丹尼尔-马科斯                 - 稍等
- I'm looking for Daniel Marks.   - Wait here.
马科斯
Marks!
不知道如何说了...
Whatever it is or how much...
- 带我走吧，男爵                   - 行。拉西呢？
- just get me out of here, Baron.  - Done. Where's de Lacy?
- 他早回泊意图了                  - 贝克特？
- He went back to Poitou.         - Becket?
你不会招他的
You don't want him.
圣殿骑士团已经回来了
Templars. They've come back.
这边。保持戒备
Here. You may need protection.
起床
Get up.
给我起床
I said, get up!
你个混蛋
You sack of shit!
Billy.
找我做什么？
What told me I'd see you?
比利又帮上帝干活了？
What's with the altar boy? Billy all tied up with God again?
- 他和我们不是一类人             - 怒了！
- This is not our man.           - Hoy!
我会追随他，别担心这些
I'm his man, don't you worry about that.
我为钱啥都敢做
If he pays me enough, I'll split the gut of any man alive.
这不就对了? 比利小子
Ain't that right, Billy boy?
- 谁跟随你？                  - 希尔-贝克特. 丹尼尔-马科斯
- Who's with you?             - Gil Becket. Daniel Marks.
上次我们在一起还是在第埃普呢
The last time we were all together must have been Dieppe.
那时候国王对咱们还不错
The days when the King was still good to us.
他已经占领了沿海的所有城堡
He's taken all the castles along the coast.
如果他占领了罗彻斯特，他就控制了英格兰南方
If he takes Rochester, he'll control southern England.
如果我得到的消息没错的话，他现在太强大了
If the whispers I've heard are true, he's too strong now.
他有一支丹麦雇佣军
He's got an army of Danish mercenaries.
还是在伦敦恭候他吧
Wait for him in London.
你认为我要这些？我不是个战士，不再是了
Do you think I want this? I'm not a soldier, not any more.
我是个有糟糠之妻和三个女儿的肥胖的羊毛商人
I'm a fat wool merchant with a hen-pecking wife and three daughters.
但，不幸的是，他不想随遇而安
But, unfortunately, he won't let it be.
抱歉，男爵，这次不一样了
I'm sorry, Baron. Not this one.
我读过十字军东征的书
I learnt about the Crusades.
圣殿之剑的传说是真的吗？
Is it true what the Templar swords say?
"耶稣的勇士被保佑而且所向披靡"
"Blessed and omnipotent is the warrior of Christ"'?
对，水。给我水
Yeah, water. Water.
- Hey!
- Agh!
你觉得他有什么价值呢？
What do you think he's worth?
- 你为你做的事后悔吗？                   - 后悔无用
- Are you sorry for what you've done?    - Bollocks.
- 放开他                - 阿门
- Release him.          - Amen!
爸爸！
Papa!
马上到里面去。
Get inside. Now!
- 约瑟夫.
- 男爵.
- 丹尼尔.
- 沃尔夫斯坦.
贝克特
Becket.
你...还是太嫩了点，贝克特
You...are a filthy whore, Becket.
她也嫩
So was she.
我们不会守住城堡
We'll never hold that castle with this lot.
他们也许不配做圣殿骑士，但他们会守住城堡
They may not be worthy of that cross you wear, but they'll hold the castle.
不是为了英格兰...不是为了上帝...
Not for England...not for God...
而是为我而战
but for me.
冬天将至，第一场雪来临前我没回来...
Winter's soon, so if I'm not back by first snowfall,
带你妹妹去叔叔那里，把这个交给他。知道了吗？
take your sister to your aunt, give her this. Hm?
努力干活
Work hard.
要有礼貌
Be polite.
上面写的是真的？
And what's written here is true?
千真万确，陛下
From my ears to this paper, Sire.
泰伯瑞斯, 即刻派六个最快的斥候赶往罗切斯特城堡
Tiberius, six of your fastest scouts to Rochester.
嘱咐他们守住城堡
Instruct them to hold the castle.
- 见到外人格杀勿论                 - 遵命！
- Kill anyone they find there.     - Hyah!
钱
Money.
你认识这些人吗？
And you know these men?
什么让你变成这样？
So what does that make you?
没用的废物
Worthless.
那里就是了
There it is.
看上去好小
Looks small from here.
那个...小城堡...
That...small castle...
却控制着天下
controls all the land as far as you can see.
耐心点，护卫
Be patient, Squire.
别和女人一样絮叨
As long as there's women.
- 来者何人？         - 兰顿大主教派我来的
- What say you?      - I bring business from Archbishop Langton.
伊莎贝尔
Isabel!
我们是一伙的
We have company.
我告诫过你，我不能容忍女人喝酒
I have told you before, I will not tolerate drinking.
你就没有容忍什么过
You won't tolerate anything.
我主。城外有人
My Lord. We have men at the gate.
我容忍国王，伊莎贝尔
I tolerate the politics of the King, Isabel.
我们的婚姻是为了土地和财富
Our marriage was arranged for land and wealth.
你记住这点就相安无事
It would be well if you were to remember that.
(顺着说)他还拥有我们的肉体和灵魂
And he owns us, body and soul.
开门！放他进来
Open the gates! Let 'em in!
你的不期而至，奥尔巴尼男爵
You arrive unexpected, Baron de Albany.
出什么事情吗？
What matter does His Grace send this late?
我们以起义的名义占领这座城堡！
That we claim this castle in the name of the rebellion.
如果你是为占领这座城堡而来，男爵...
If your visit is to claim my castle, Baron...
你迟了一步
you're too late.
不常见的坐鞍
Unusual saddles.
- 丹麦人           - 什么？
- Danish.          - What was that?
几个丹麦人，昨晚就到了
They're Danish. They arrived last night.
国王的斥候。他的大军距离这里不到一天的行程
The King's scouts. His army is less than a day away.
奥克斯, 快叫卫兵来
Oaks, get the guard here quickly.
两天前那人还在达尔奈的城堡
That one was at Darnay Castle two days ago.
Aargh!
Argh!
No. No, no!
马歇尔, 蹲下来！
Marshal, down!
Yargh!
男爵
Baron.
别轻举妄动！站住不许动
Stand down! Stand down!
听我说
Listen to me.
依据大主教的名义，我们宣布这个城堡起义
By the archbishop, we claim this castle in the name of the rebellion.
起义结束了啊。国王向《大宪章》投降
The rebellion's over. The King surrendered to the great charter.
《大宪章》
Magna Carta.
这个是国王亲手签署发布的
This one sealed by the King's own hand.
但现在...他却在处决每一个支持《大宪章》的人
And now... he's executing everybody who supported it.
可是教皇是否知道大主教在皇家城堡里头宣告反抗国王的事？
But does the Pope know that the Archbishop is claiming royal castles, against the King?
我目睹我三个兄弟被杀
I watched as three of my brothers were killed
国王的暴行正在毁了他的统治之路
by the soft hand of a king that is murdering his way across the country.
而且他还没有一丝忏悔
And he does so with the Pope's blessing.
法国军队已经出洋开进了
The French army make sail any day now.
让我们...另立一个新国王
Giving us...a new king.
一个英明的国王
A true king.
关闭城门
Seal the gates.
锁上所有的大门！快行动！奥克斯, 别让任何人进来
Lock all the doors! Move! And, Oaks, no one else comes in.
好吧
Very well.
好吧，马歇尔...
Well, Marshal...
你来领导防守这个城堡吧
you got us our castle.
- 队长，你的手下呢？                - 11个全副武装的战士
- What is your strength, Captain?   - Eleven men-at-arms.
- 我们还不到20人？                  - 这些城墙
- We have less than 20 men?         - And these walls.
- 他们未遭背弃                   - 内城碉堡有吊闸吗？
- They've never been breached.   - Does the keep have a portcullis?
- 有                  - 好
- It does.            - Good.
- 一旦关门，就没人进的来             - 水. 水源在哪里？
- Once it's down, no one gets in.    - Water. Where is the supply?
井里，直接来源于河水。水源充足
From the Well. Draws straight from the river. No one here gets thirsty.
- 不错。水质没问题吧？                    - 水质不错
- it's good, it's not sick or brackish?   - Water's good, sir.
小伙子，跟我来
Guy, with me.
这些城墙设计成保护每个点的战士
These walls are designed to be defended by one man per station.
外观完美。 任何一处都可以看到几英里远
Outlook is perfect. Any approach can be seen for miles.
现在，咱们去大门警戒室（建于通道之上）瞧瞧
Now, let's see the gatehouse.
你们，日以继夜，保持警惕。现在打开城门
You, day or night, stay alert. Now open it up.
有什么问题？
What's the problem?
没有护城河
There's no moat.
这个行
That'll do.
现在，他们来袭时...
Now, when they come...
..狠狠打
..hit them hard.
打打靶子看看
Hit the post.
我是说，狠狠地打靶子
I said, hit the post. Hard.
法国援军会来吧？
They'll come? The French.
以前在达玛斯库战役中，我们盼望的法国援军就没来
We waited for the French at Damascus. They didn't come then.
指望法国人会来有点像赌博
Even to a Frenchman I think Rochester is nearer than Damascus.
继续练习
Hit it.
年轻人，你最好更用力点打
You better hit it harder than that, boy.
否则那些援军还没来你就先死了
Or you'll be dead before they get here.
他们恨女人
They hate women.
觉得咱们没啥用
Just to look at one's a sin.
一些人说他们来铲除邪恶
Some people say they worship the devil.
铁石心肠
Celibates with stone hearts.
我也铁石心肠，Maddy.
Then I have a stone heart, too, Maddy.
我并非这个意思
I didn't mean it like that.
圣殿骑士团要求忠实于上帝
A Templar offers his Chastity to God,
但是妻子...
but a wife...
她需要忠实于丈夫
she suffers hers by her husband.
我丈夫对我没兴趣
My husband's appetites don't include me.
感谢圣母玛利亚
Thank the Lord Mary herself.
我很...好奇，奥尔巴尼
Now, I am... "curious, Albany.
为何你和你的朋友们如此执着于起义？
Why is it that you and your friends are so struck with this rebellion?
- 嗯                 - 我们是为了人民
- Mm.                - Cos we are for the people.
我看到你训练有素多才多艺
I see your esquire is well-trained in the art of naivety.
- 继续说             - 你可以认为我幼稚
- Go on.             - Call me naive if you will, sir,
但是人们讨厌一个禽兽般的国王
but the people deserve more than a king that treats them like animals.
哈，护卫的大论
Ah, bold words for a Squire.
你读过《大宪章》吗
Have you read Magna Carta?
- 我...              - 哈，我明白了。你不懂拉丁文
- I...               - Ah, I see. You can't read Latin.
可惜呀，忽视争论
It's a pity, arguing from ignorance.
(说外国话，大伙儿都惊呆了)
Argumentum ad ignorantiam, ab uno disce omnes.
那是罗马人的语言吧？
That's Roman, innit?
翻译过来就是“从个体入手了解众人”
From one person, learn all people.
原谅我妻子醒目的嘴巴
Excuse my wife's bold tongue.
贝克特, 我要去你远端的墙
Becket, I'm gonna need you on the far wall.
- 小伙子没办法单独防御              - 你亲自来执行
- Guy can't defend it on his own.   - Do it yourself.
什么？
What?
想喝一杯？女人
You want a drink? A woman?
不要拿你的臭脸对着我
Don't you sniff your nose at me.
我在很多场合。我见证你圣洁的兄弟们的所做所为
I've been places. I've seen what your holy brothers have done.
你们虚伪的做法让我恶心
Your pious bile makes me sick.
贝克特. 到外面去
Becket. I want you outside.
我会帮那个小伙子，但谁来帮我
I'll watch your boy's back, but who's watching mine?
警报！
To the battlements!
- 警报                        - 动作快
- To the battlements!         - Right away!
- 各就各位                    - 迅速集结
- Take your positions, men!   - Get those men up here, quickly!
梅采尔, 他们在那
Mercel, they're here!
让我们瞧瞧天会不会塌下来
Let's see what rats have taken up in my home.
动作迅速点
Move it! Come on!
奥尔巴尼,一句话，你不能不顾及协议
Albany, a word. You cannot engage the King without considering terms.
他要我的人头呢。那协议也有这个内容吗？
He wants our heads on spikes. Where are the terms in that?
打战，顾及不了太多了
There are some in here who didn't pick this fight.
问自己为何而战，Cornhill
Ask yourself who you're for, Cornhill.
国王还是国家？因为我们都没错
The King or the country? Because we both can't be wrong.
他们来了
They're here.
奥尔巴尼
Albany!
他怎么知道我在这？有什么需要我们效劳的？约翰
How did he know? What can we do for you, John?
威廉de奥尔巴尼男爵
William de Albany男爵.
教皇授令我恢复王权
The Pope has ordered me to reclaim my country.
现在，你确定关门对抗国王，和教廷？
Now, surely you don't bar your door against a king, and the Church?
他是否知道你原先签署颁布宪章...
Does he know you sealed a charter...
给予英格兰平民自由
giving the people of England freedom,
然后现在你又反悔了？
and that now you go back on your word?
英格兰是我的，奥尔巴尼
England is mine, Albany.
君权神授，教皇授意我的
God's will bestowed it unto me, the Pope blesses it to me,
而且这个城堡是属于我的
and this castle belongs to me!
（奥尔巴尼对着约翰王）你这个国王...
You're no more a king...
连我屁股上的疮都不如
than the boil on my arse!
Huh.
（奥尔巴尼对他的朋友们）多么无聊的一个小矮人
What a tedious little man.
准备开战
Get the swords now. Come on!
大家赶紧行动
Move yourselves!
各就各位
Stay by your posts.
记住，他们要翻越城墙
Remember, they have to climb over these walls.
而我们不需翻越
And we do not.
因此要坚守阵地
So you stand firm!
你有以少敌众过吗？
Have you ever fought so many with so few?
嗯哈。别忘记守住城墙了
Uh-huh. Don't you forget, you hold the wall, huh?
现在，回你的岗位上去
Now, go to your post.
南北分列
North and south advance!
弓箭手准备
Get ready, archers!
发射
Loose!
注意空中来袭
Take cover!   Incoming
再一波！射
And again! Take cover!
快闪开
Get down!
Ha-ha!
坚守岗位
Come on, lads, come on! Take your positions! Look lively!
射，给我射
Take cover, lads! Take cover!
Argh!
再一波
Again!
Argh!
奥尔巴尼
Albany!
弓箭手！他们进攻了
Archers! They're coming!
准备好了吗？
Make a stand! Ready?
拉满弓
Load arrows!
射
Loose!
- 油！扔油弹                 - 准备
- Oil! Bring up that oil!    - Ready!
射
Loose!
油！小心背后
Oil! Watch your back!
支援
Take cover!
贝克特
Becket!
这边来
Come on. This way.
- 我们做点什么？        - 祈祷上帝与他们同在
- What do we do?        - Pray God is with them.
贝克特
Becket!
Ha, ha-ha-ha-ha!
年轻人
Guy!
去见圣母吧
Show that to your mother!
起来
Now, get up!
给我起来
I said get up!
狠狠地打
Now, you hit him. Hard!
在你身后！清除掉
Behind you! Clear!
支援！
Take cover!
Aargh!
他们撤退了
They're running!
他们被吓跑了，他们受够了，男爵
They're retreating! They've had enough, Baron.
狗杂种！去吧，给我滚！
Bastards! Go on, run!
来啊，你们这些外国佬
Come on, you foreign whores!
作战勇敢
You fought bravely.
很多事你还未领略
You did not see everything.
领略了却再也无法宁静
There's no finding peace after knowing this.
信念，小伙子
Faith, Guy.
只有微弱的信仰...
Only the weak believe that what they do in battle...
战斗让你成熟
is who they are as men.
把他们放在一起
Put him with the others.
把他们放在那边，就这样
Pack 'em over there. Over there, that's it.
奥尔巴尼男爵...
Baron Albany...
还不到一天...
in less than a day...
你把我的城堡搅得乌烟瘴气
you have stripped away everything I gave the people in this castle.
- 天塌了我顶着            - 你都自身难保
- Get off my back.        - You were hellbent on this fight!
我们被你拖下水了，还起义
You made us all hostages to your cause, not the rebellion's.
而且这也并非其他城堡
And this was not just another castle!
这是我的城堡
This was my home!
现在把你拉的屎清洗干净
Now clear your mess up.
把门关上
Shut the door.
就是现在
Still now.
在这儿等下
Wait. Here.
- 这个人流血了               - 放桌上
- This man is bleeding.      - On the table.
别。等等。先止血
No. Wait. This will stop the flow.
用力按住
I'm gonna pull this hard.
骨头没断，但...
The bone's not broken, but...
继续，来吧
Go on, do it, do it.
清理一下，细心照料他
Keep it clean, and watch him close.
圣殿骑士
Templar.
- 你的脖子           - 别
- Your neck.         - No.
坐下
Sit.
请坐下
Please.
如果没止住血，我该不该给你脖子打绷带呢？
If the bleeding doesn't stop, shall I fasten a belt around your neck?
有人告诉我你不能眷恋女色
My maid tells me you cannot look at women.
你叫什么？
What is your name?
沉默是不是也意味着你不能和女性说话呢？
Am I to assume your silence means you cannot talk to women either?
我叫托马斯-马歇尔
My name is Thomas Marshal.
好了
There it is.
起义是否总伴随着牺牲
And were many sacred vows broken by that revelation?
这不像其他的，河流是天然的屏障
It's not like the others. The river naturally defends.
城墙建的... 所以不多人就挡住了大军
Walls built... so a few can stop many.
别耍我了，队长
Don't insult me, Captain.
我知道对方的兵力
I know the qualities of a Norman keep.
我特别困惑的是...
What I am having trouble with...
1000人的大军居然打不过那20人
is how a thousand men could have failed so miserably against twenty.
这么辛苦作战，为了什么？
Those men fight hard. For what?
就为了这个屁点大的的堡垒？
A small rock in a field?
我们绕行
We go around.
我曾曾祖父建造了那座堡垒
My great, great grandfather built that rock
那是他征服了整个国家
when he conquered this country.
他关系到伦敦和整个英格兰南部的控制权
Strategically, it fortifies London and controls all of southern England.
为什么你不考虑他们要选择这里阻击我们
Why in God's name do you think they chose to hole up there in the first place?
去激励下军心，队长
What will please your people more, Captain?
你的手下战死在一场伟大的战役
That your men died in a great battle,
或者说你对我的帮助的回报是教会独自离开你的土地
or that your reward for helping me is the Church leaving your lands alone?
因为那是教皇答应的，所有他会这样做
For that is what the Pope promised he would do.
不论希望多么渺茫...
Now, however small it may seem...
..这个堡垒带头了，全国各地都会效仿的
..with that rock, the rest of this country follows.
现在你可以按照他的意思去做
Now you see what he means to do.
我对你们每个人说
I say this to each of you.
现在天正黑...
There's a night out there...
黑的足够让人逃跑而不被发现
deep enough for a man to slip away, if he should wish.
而且我很清醒
And I would understand.
我觉得你触犯了他
I think you upset him.
马科斯，你的意见呢？
What about you, Marks?
我特地为你从昂古莱姆来的
I took this for you at Angouléme.
我走进图卢兹的外围
I walked into this outside Toulouse.
有两次我们看到有人逃跑，你以为我在这里做什么啊?
Both times we saw it through. What do you think I'm doing here?
我可不想收了别人的钱就跑了
I don't take a man's money and run.
菲普斯先生，你和你的手下还继续战斗吗？
Mr Phipps, are you and your garrison men still for the fight?
总共六个人，健全待命
All six of us. Good and ready, sir.
Ah!
我看到你和圣殿骑士一起
I saw you with the Templar.
我觉得他合乎你的心意
I think he has a mind for you.
我并不在意他心里想什么
His mind possesses nothing I care to think about.
他有些不同寻常处。他是个战斗狂人
There is something not normal with him. It's his manner.
我少言寡语
He looks but won't talk.
他也没什么好和我说的
Then he talks and nothing he says settles with me.
别说他生来如此。我根本不相信
Don't tell me that was his way before he became a Templar. I wouldn't believe it.
- 夫人        - 什么事？
- My Lady.    - What?
要好好考虑考虑...
That's a great deal of thinking...
有些人就不想去动脑筋
for someone you don't want to think about.
Hm.
他们在建造什么。
They're building something.
什么东西？
What do you think it is?
皇家工程师，陛下
Your royal engineer, Sire.
- 这管用吗？           - 没有护城河，恩...所以，恩...
- Will it work?        - There's no moat, er... So, er...
没有护城河也没有借口。赶紧做好
There's no moat and no excuses. Finish it.
告诉他要做好...
Tell him to construct a...
我不该那样说你
I am sorry for what I said to you.
我错了
I was wrong.
我们接下去会如何？
What happens next...to us?
- 我们？               - 他们会再进攻
- All of us?           - They will attack again.
我们会再守住
And we will hold again.
法国人...
The French...
...海运军队来支持我们
..made sail with an army to stand by us.
你相信他们会来？
You really believe they will come?
恩
Hm.
别骗我, 托马斯
Thou shall not lie, Thomas.
当然不是为了法国人
Certainly not for the French.
不只是我这么说。你这么做不值得
Definitely not to me. It isn't worth it.
这些触犯了圣殿的法规？
Does that break Templar laws?
Mm.
某些人可能会说“行”
Some would say yes.
把剑放下
Put the sword down.
他们攻来时，我要知道我怎么用这个
If they do come, I will need to know how to use this.
- 这样握着吗？               - 如果你想让对方赢
- Is this how you hold it?   - If you want your opponent to win.
我打战...
I fight...
...但你不必参与
..so you don't have to.
攻城塔
Siege tower.
他们在建造攻城塔。该死
Making quick work of it. Damn it.
男爵，我有个主意
Baron, I have an idea.
如果这个不管用下场会如何？
What happens if this doesn't work?
- 别问这么多         - 还有更糟糕的吗？
- Don't ask.         - What could be worse than this?
护卫，你杀过哪怕是一个女人吗?
Squire, would you ever kill a woman?
- 没杀过         - 那有不让她受辱而不得不杀一个女人？
- Never.         - Not even if it meant saving her life?
就是它了，放下来
That's it, heave it down.
圣骑士约瑟夫！看到没有
Holy Saint Joseph! Look who it is.
神器准备好了
His Majesty is ready, my Lord.
- 路易王子还呆在法国             - 他们还没出发？
- Prince Louis holds in France.  - They haven't sailed yet?
- 好像在谈条款                          - 谈判
- He's buying time to negotiate terms.  - Negotiate terms!
国王奴役国家
The King enslaves this country,
教皇支持他废弃《大宪章》
the Pope defends him and calls the Magna Carta heresy,
法国人拿这个做交易
and France uses this tyranny for a better deal?
- 难道没人愿意作战？                   - 只有一部分
- Are there any men willing to fight?  - A few.
大部分人认为约翰王签署了《大宪章》起义已经过时了
Many thought the rebellion was over because John signed the Magna Carta.
看来他死掉是最明智的结局了
In some ways, it was the smartest thing he did.
好，万事具备，一切按照计划进行
Well, all that is done.
让罗马爱说什么说什么吧
Let Rome pronounce whatever holy dictum it pleases.
他们不会告诉我上帝归他们的
They won't tell me that God is their possession.
我动身去法国。你尽量招兵买马
I leave for France at once. You gather what men you can.
准备伦敦之战
And prepare London for war.
那罗切斯特城堡呢？
And Rochester?
- 那奥尔巴尼男爵呢?     - 但愿上帝和他们同在
- Baron Albany?         - Pray God is with them.
支援
Take cover!
好极了。好极了
Excellent. Excellent.
继续推，再快点
Go on. Faster!
锁定
Lock it!
- 锁定              - 开火
- Lock!             - And fire!
新造了设备？
They have built an engine?
Yargh!
支援！
Take cover!
你们全到外边去
All of you, outside.
沃尔夫斯坦, 被冲破了
Wulfstan, you've broken through!
来吧！让他们见识下地狱火
Now, come on! Give them hellfire!
放！放
Heave! Heave!
Aargh!
锁定它！火盆给我，小伙子
Lock it! Fire pot, Guy!
你们这些异教徒走狗
You heathen dogs!
向前推进点
Bring it a bit forward!
点火！点火！
Light it! Light it!
发射
Loose!
Yeah!
可恶！真见鬼
Goddamn devils! Murdering goddamn whores!
好，攻城车着火了
Yes! They burn!
别记载这些
Do not record that!
狗屎
Bitches!
你这个混蛋国王，沃尔夫斯坦
This bastard king, Wulfstan.
Aye.
此后，国王不敢再来了
After that, the king did not come again.
但雨水悄然而至
But the rains did.
天气逐渐转凉了
And the days grew short as autumn turned to winter.
在饥寒交迫中坚持战斗
They were too cold to Fight, and too hungry.
城堡的物资储备已经不足...
The castle stores were empty...
大家已经吃掉了好多马
and they had taken to eating the horses.
马圈里仅有一匹马了
Save for one.
马歇尔的坐骑
Marshal's.
但圣殿骑士禁止吃自己的战马
But a Templar is forbidden to eat his horse.
战马只能战死在沙场
Their Order dictates that it must die in battle.
12个饥饿的灵魂和仅剩的一匹战马
So 13 hungry souls and one horse would remain.
他们依旧在等待救援
Still they waited.
国王这方也在等待
And so too did the King.
他们可以闻到敌军的食物，听到敌军的歌曲
They could smell his food, hear his army's song.
对于人员耗损是一个人的盟友和另一个人的诅咒
For attrition is one man's ally and another man's curse.
因此他们变成了受诅咒的人
So they became cursed men.
经过一段时间后
And as weeks turned to months,
他们会觉得...
their minds took to places they should not...
不值得这么做
where a man sees only doubt and has no worth at all.
婚礼上我就知道我的婚姻和爱无关
On my wedding day I knew my marriage would have no love.
我仍然坚持我读上帝的忠诚
Yet still I took my vows to God.
我很自豪并遵守承诺
I honoured and obeyed my commitments daily.
你认为我们不一样，托马斯，但你错了
You think we are not the same, Thomas, but you're wrong.
- 我快饿死了           - 你想怎么做？
- I'm starving!        - What do you want me to do?
必须做点什么
Someone's gotta do something!
听我说
Listen to me.
圣殿骑士誓言见鬼去吧
Damn your Templar vows!
我的誓言造就了我
It was my vows that made me what I am.
指引我，带我来到这里
It was my Order that brought me here.
还有神的恩典
And by God's good grace,
圣殿骑士才真正为你们出生入死
it will be the Templars that save your life.
你要去哪里？
Where are you going?
你干嘛走人？
Why are you leaving?
他为何离去？
Why would he leave?
你最后见到他
My Lady, you were with him last.
他有否说为什么要离开？
Did he say why he left?
回你房间去
You go to your chamber.
立刻
Now.
不
No.
他要回来才怪呢
I'll kiss the Bishop's arse if he comes back.
他们会回来的，贝克特
You're gonna have to kiss a king's arse,
Becket, cos they're coming back again.
- 是托马斯            - 开门
- it's Thomas!        - Open the gates!
贝克特，接应他！
Becket, get him! Get him, Becket!
快啊！帮帮他！接住袋子，袋子！
Come oh! Quickly! Help him! Get the sacks. The sacks!
- 快来！              - 快
- Come on!            - Hurry!
- 跑！                - 放下吊闸！
- Run!                - Close the portcullis!
你怎么想的？圣殿骑士
What was you thinking, Templar?
他去偷国王的食物。我从没见过这种事
He's stolen the king's food. I've never seen such a thing!
你被解除职务了，队长
You are relieved of your command, Captain.
坐你的木舟回老家去吧
Get back in your rowboat and go home.
- 没我的人我不走！                 - 哦对，你不走
- I'm not leaving without my men!  - Oh yes, you are!
我告诉你原因。教皇改变主意了
And I will tell you why. The Pope has had a change of heart.
你说什么？
What do you say?
我是说，之前招你来打仗
I say that when your pathetic little army arrives back at your houses,
现在你可以回家去了
you will find your lands Christianised.
不然的话，你孩子们将给教会做奴隶，你妻子会改嫁
Your sons enslaved to the Church and your wives serving new husbands.
你从没和教皇说过我的领土？
You did not speak to the Pope of my lands?
为什么我以上帝的名义做这些事？
Why in God's name would I do that?
占领城堡，泰伯瑞斯!
Take this castle, Tiberius!
如果失败了，你将流浪回家
And if you do not, you will be sailing home to quite a different world.
Marshal, 你真太牛逼了
Well, Marshal, you sure know how to pick a bit of shank.
比三个月的马肉餐好太多了
Better than three months of horse meat.
我该吃了就睡。然后呢？
I'll stick with the pig. Then what?
吃掉你
I'll eat you.
Oh!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
护卫...
So, Squire...
你认得字吗？
you can read words?
也会写吗？
And write them too?
你全名叫什么？
What's your full name?
Jedediah Coteral.
Yeah.
我头回见到自己的全民是这么写的
I've never seen it written before. Huh.
Hm.
静悄悄的。去查看一下城墙另一头
It's too quiet. Check the far wall.
发现敌情！攻击！
To the battlements! Attack!
支援侧翼。侧翼！
Cover the west wing. West wing! Come on!
- 小心               - 来右边
- Watch out!         - To the right!
快救我
Help me!
大门！大门！
The gates! The gates!
马歇尔哪里去了？
Where's Marshal?
战斗！战斗！
Fight, Guy! Fight!
男爵！
Baron!
Aargh!
男爵！
Baron!
别动。就这样
Don't move. Be still.
- 守住内城碉堡          - 你不能死
- Hold the keep.        - You can't die.
你不能死，好好活下去！听到了吗？
You can't die. Stay alive! You hear me?
守住内城碉堡！去！快去！
Hold the keep! Go! Go!
Yaargh!
菲普斯
Phipps!
- 来这                  - 顶住大门
- Come here!            - Hold the gates!
我顶住.我顶住
I've got it. I've got it.
快来，到大门这里来
Come on, to the gates!
顶住！
Hold!
都过来！都过来顶
All in! All in!
快站好
Stand fast!
盾墙！
Shield wall!
盾牌。举起盾牌！
Shields. Shields up!
举起
Up!
Brace yourselves.
准备！预备！
Ready! Ready!
- 伊莎贝尔       - 到里面去
- Isabel!        - Get inside!
即刻
Now!
- 我们去保护男爵！              - 去内城碉堡
- We have to get to the Baron!  - To the keep!
- 我们不能撇下他          - 他死了
- We can't leave him!     - He's gone, all right?
稳住！稳住！
Hold the steps! Hold the steps!
来吧
Come on!
马歇尔
Marshal!
砍死他
Pull him down!
马歇尔！快来
Marshal! Come on!
让开！让开！
Get it off! Get it off!
回到吊闸背后去
Get back, behind the portcullis!
快点
Come on!
那些囚犯
They have prisoners.
小子
Boy!
下午好，男爵。我的城堡还是归我好
Good afternoon, Baron. Did you find my castle to your liking?
这是人民的城堡
It's the people's castle now.
你不是说他死了吗？
You said he was gone.
把这两个，手和脚全砍掉
Those two. Cut off their hands and feet.
- No.
- No!
No!
现在，男爵，我要有所保留
Now, Baron, I want my keep back.
- 听我指令                - 别！
- At my command!          - No!
- 他们不会投降                 - 真的？
- They'll never surrender.     - Really?
动手
Do it!
动手啊！我们守住内城碉堡
Do something! We hold the keep.
你这个暴君！
My arse, your stinking castle!
Aaargh!
Aargh!
你该死，你连妓女都杀
God damn you, you murdering whore!
我不是国王吗？
Isn't that the king I am?
你不行王道
You betray all that's meant to be king.
你背叛了上帝
You betray God!
我背叛了上帝？！
I betray God?!
我的王位是我父亲传给我哥哥，我哥哥再传给我的
My crown was passed to me by my brother, and my father before him.
我生来就是王
I was born to be a king!
这个是天注定的！君权神授！
It is my birthright! Given to me by God!
你为普通人哭喊
You cry for the common man
你诅咒保护着我的皇冠！
and in the same breath you curse the crown that protects him!
你胆敢质疑我的统治...
You dare to question my reign...
和我之前的国王王室血统
and the lineage of Kings who have reigned before me?!
伟大不朽的阿基坦皇家...
The great amaranthine royalty of Aquitaine...
..从野蛮的游牧部落得到这片土地...
..who forged this land from barbarian hordes
而且血统变得高贵而且纯正
and made it noble and pure!
我代表着权力
Who gave it order, meaning,
甚至代表着信仰
and even faith...
代表着千百年来的忠诚臣民
to thousands of years of loyal subjects!
它就是所有你现在质疑的
And it is all now questioned by you!
而且我们被迫签署《大宪章》
And we are forced to sign your precious Magna Carta,
就是你这个羊毛商人逼迫的
forced by you, a wool merchant!
我是有血性的！我是上帝之手
I am the blood! I am God's right hand!
而且你将永远不会向我发号施令，我是一个国王
And you will never dictate to me how I am to be a king!
现在，男爵
Now, Baron.
该先砍下那边手呢？
Which hand did you touch me with?
砍下他的手
Hold his hand down.
砍下他的右手！
Hold his right hand down!
你不该看这个
This is not something you should see.
Aargh!
告诉你的同伙开门，奥尔巴尼
Tell your rebels to open the gate, Albany!
不投降！
No surrender!
- 不投降          - 砍下他的手！动手！
- No surrender!   - Put his other hand up! Do it!
动手
Do it!
Aargh!
我们能守得住，男爵！
We hold, Baron!
我们坚定不移
We hold!
砍下他的脚，砍下他的脚来！
Put his feet up. Put his feet up!
Cornhill!
你会向国王屈服的！
You will yield to your king!
或者，上帝作证，你的死期不远了
Or, as God hears me, your head is on a spike!
现在，给他上套吊死他
Now, that monster that they've made, strap his carcass to it.
吊死他
Strap him to it!
Heave!
没有援军？
There's no one coming, is there?
斥候报告法国人出兵了
My scouts report the French have left Calais.
几天后他们就会绕道我们的背后
They'll be at our back within days.
你知道吗？当我小时候，
Do you know that when I was a child,
我曾经爱上了我父亲的宠妃
I once secretly ate every urn of my father's beloved honey peaches.
接下去的日子里...
And the next day...
他把我带到这个女人面前
he brought before me a servant girl that he had accused of the crime.
他把她的后按在桌子上，然后掏出了刀...
And he placed her hand on the table, and he drew his knife...
...他执行了惩处
..and he delivered the punishment.
然后那个夜晚，也无法掩饰我的羞愧
And that night, unable to contain my shame,
我对他坦白是我干的，
I confessed to him that it was I,
他的犯罪的儿子
his son, who had committed the crime.
你知道他怎么回应的吗？
Do you know what his response was?
他说，“我了解”
He said, "l know.
“我了解”
"l know.
"这就是我只砍断她的手指的理由"
"And that is why I only cut off her finger.
“你要了解，约翰，任何胆敢挑战王权的行为
"You see, John, any action against the throne
都必须得到惩罚”
"must be punished ruthlessly.
“只有这种方式来维系
"For that is the only way to maintain the absolute power...
国王绝对的权力”
"..of a king."
他们来时，你要求觐见国王
When they come, you must demand to see the King.
我不指望他
I want nothing from him.
没有任何的怜悯
Not even mercy.
我违背了诺言，Isabel
I broke my vow, Isabel.
辜负了上帝的信赖
I have betrayed God's trust.
我有罪
What we did was a sin.
别逃避了...誓言和命令的借口没用
Stop hiding... behind vows and commandments.
忠诚和禁欲以及谋杀的誓言，但...
The vows speak of loyalty and abstinence and murder, but...
为何没有爱？
why never love, Thomas?
我在上帝面前发誓...
The vows of the Order...
...绝不滥杀无辜，但我玷污了上帝
..protect my soul from the blood I've spilt in God's name.
是教会让你这么干的
It was the Church that made you do those things.
是圣殿骑士团给予你武器
It was the Templars that gave you a sword
以上帝的名义来使用它
and the name of God to wield it.
是圣殿骑士团让你杀戮
It was the Templars that made you kill.
你没入会之前什么身份？
Who were you before them?
是谁使你一改初衷的?
What was so bad about that man then that makes you resist your desires now?
托马斯...
Thomas...
我没罪
I am not a sin.
陛下？陛下？
Sire? Sire?
竣工了，陛下。地道好了
Your engineer, sire. The mine is ready.
管用吗？
Will it work?
- 正好在内城碉堡底部的下方                    - 好
- it's right under the keep's foundations.    - Ah.
记录下来
Then take note.
通知司法官送40头猪给我
To my justiciar, send to me 40 pigs.
至少还能用来吃
The least good for eating.
即刻起运
Deliver that at once.
Come on! Hurry up! Move it!
That's it.
- 你去哪？            - 我打算去讲和
- Where you going?    - I'm going to plead for terms.
No!
没别的办法了吗？我们坚定守住
What else is there to do? We hold.
坚持到底等谁来？法国人？他们不会来了
We hold for What? The French? They're not coming.
- 我去谈判              - 别
- I'll ask for terms.   - No!
我们发过誓。誓言！
We swore an oath. An oath!
为了奥尔巴尼。为了英格兰
To Albany. To England.
誓言是空的
Your oath is worthless.
《大宪章》是空的
Magna Carta is worthless.
教会都废除宪章了
The Church has annulled it.
这里发生的一切都毫无意义
Whatever happens here is meaningless.
No. No. Wait!
- 够了，护卫                - 贝克特?
- That's enough, Squire.    - Becket?
这个年轻人想杀了那老头
Your boy here tried to take the old man's head off.
贝克特, 放开他
Becket, leave him be.
现在，年轻人...放开他
Now, Guy...get away from him.
- 马上             - 凭什么？
- Now.             - Or what?
你要杀了我？
You'll kill me?
- 年轻人...        - 住嘴
- Guy...           - Shut up!
奥尔巴尼男爵为了信仰牺牲了
Baron de Albany gave his life for his beliefs.
你能做得到吗？
What have you given for yours?
胆小鬼
Coward.
回天无力啊
There's no salvation to this end.
我们...
Our souls...
太丢人了
are damned.
你不是胆小鬼
You are not a coward.
- 你在干什么？           - 写自己的大名啊
- What are you doing?    - I'm writing my name.
你会写？
How do you do that?
小师傅教我的
Master Guy taught me.
你就做这个
Well, that's you all done then.
你有什么好气的？
What makes a man like you so angry?
我一直来气...
I've been angry so long...
我甚至不记得气了多久
I don't even remember.
我觉得你会幸存
It's kept you alive though, I suppose.
我觉得我们过不了这道难关
I don't think it's gonna get us through this one.
- 他们在做什么？                     - 猪油，工兵的火药
- What do you think they're doing?   - Pigs. For a sapper's fire.
- 工兵？              - 他们在我们底下挖地道
- Sappers?            - They're digging a mine underneath us.
猪的脂肪，在热坩埚上燃烧
Pig's fat, it burns, with the heat of a crucible.
开道
Make Way!
继续！前进
Go on! Go!
哇啊
Whoa!
Whoa there!
哇啊
Whoa!
带进来
Bring them in.
大事不好了
We've got a bigger problem.
上去
Hah! Get in there!
继续！
Go on!
Coteral.
好热
It's hot.
- 那现在怎么做？                  -圣殿骑士
- So what are we gonna do now?    - Templar.
我们去守内城碉堡的另一边
We get to the other side of the keep.
小伙子，带女人去礼拜堂 唔？
Guy, take the women to the chapel, huh?
快去
Go!
赶紧，Isabel
Hurry, Isabel.
下去！下去！
Get down! Get down!
- 我以为他死了               - 我不会再犯错
- I think he's gone.         - I'm not making that mistake again.
来吧
Come on.
喔 一，二
OK.One, two.
噢, Maddy. 她一直伴随我
Oh, Maddy. She was beside me.
贝克特
Becket. Becket.
Ha!
截住他们
I'll hold them Off.
他们付你多少钱让你干这些？
How much did they pay to get you out those stocks?
- 五个先令(英镑之下的货币单位)   - 比妓女还贱
- Five shillings.                - That is cheaper than a whore.
来吧，你这污秽的婊子
Come on, you filthy whores!
如果敌人突破进来，你就杀了妇女
If they get through us, you kill the women.
- 不              - 口头重复下指令
- No.             - Say it.
- 我做不到        - 口头重复下指令!
- I can't.        - Say it!
我会杀了妇女
I'll kill the women.
Come on, you whore! Yaargh!
Aargh!
原谅我
Forgive me.
托马斯
Thomas. Thomas!
Thomas!
去救她
Save her.
都不许动
No one touch him!
你现在感觉如何？圣殿骑士
How's your faith now, Templar?
你为什么不靠近点呢...
Why don't you come a little closer...
...我就告诉你
..and I'll show you.
Yaaargh!
你真勇敢
You fought bravely.
杀戮是件高尚之事吗？
Is killing a noble thing?
但是为他人而战就没白活
But a life fought for others is a life worth living.
这就很高尚了
That is a noble thing.
法国援军来了
A French prince now holds the English crown.
做决定并不容易
Not an easy decision to make.
就像这次
托马斯，结束了教会的服役
你自由了
Your Grace.
来啊
我们坚持住了
不到一年，起义获胜了
约翰王因痢疾而亡
他剩下的财富销声匿迹
期间，伟大的罗切斯特的内城碉堡被重新建造
至今仍屹立不倒
高尚的梦想也同样屹立在那里的是...《大宪章》
( 谢谢观赏。中文字幕校对翻译：passarella )